<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decision-making on Known Unknowns</title>
    <link>/categories/decision-making/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decision-making on Known Unknowns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/decision-making/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Black Box</title>
      <link>/2019/10/06/the-black-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/06/the-black-box/</guid>
      <description>The concept of a black box was developed in the 1940’s as a device that recorded the various readings of aircraft instruments. The purpose was to be accessible in the event of a crash so that investigators could understand the conditions leading to the tragedy in the hopes of learning how to avoid it in the future. Today we often see it in the context of decision-making, usually associated with shadowy “Artificial Intelligence” and “Algorithmic Learning,” all that techy stuff that journalists and politicians don’t get some times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the rules!</title>
      <link>/2019/05/15/what-are-the-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/15/what-are-the-rules/</guid>
      <description>Harking back to our golden tri-force of process, product and culture I wanted to discuss today; process. And like a high school level research paper let’s start with a google definition:
“[Process] is a series of actions or steps taken in order to achieve a particular end.”
That’s pretty straight forward. You could compare it to a function in mathematics, given an input \(A\) how do you get to output \(B\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit</title>
      <link>/2018/12/15/brexit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/15/brexit/</guid>
      <description>Back again! And what a month we have had in the UK. In case you didn’t know, I used to work in Canadian Politics, which compared to the rest of the world (especially these days) is quite tame. But politics is something I am passionate about. I like to think of myself as civilly minded democrat committed to reflecting the will of the people into robust and positive policy. Others might disagree, you know who you are ;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>