<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NHS on Known Unknowns</title>
    <link>/categories/nhs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NHS on Known Unknowns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/nhs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Test</title>
      <link>/2020/05/01/r-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/01/r-test/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR The UK government has released a series of communications outlining the five tests they will use to track and inform COVID-19 lockdown measures. The government&amp;rsquo;s video regarding an infection rate, or R value, is a great example of data driven storytelling.
TS:WM This one will be short
  This will be a short one. See the video above. I have been following the COVID-19 crisis with great interest, not only from a geo-political perspective but because of the challenges it presents in terms of data while we search for facts and truth about the virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fudging Numbers</title>
      <link>/2020/04/29/fudging-numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/29/fudging-numbers/</guid>
      <description>First off, a sincere thank you to all front line medical workers across the globe, particularly the NHS. You are all heros in the face of a dangerous situation and your contribution is felt by your patients and the public alike. We can never repay you for the sacrifices you are making and we all pray an event like this will never be seen again. To everyone else, if you are so moved, why not join the NHS Volunteer Army and help save lives today!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>